I understand once you're on TRT, you're
on it for life, but at what age is it
recommended to lower the dosages?
>> So, a couple of things there. I mean,
are you on it for life? You you can come
off it. You can stop. You're going to go
back to feeling as crappy as you did
before. So, there so there's that. Um,
you know, it might take you three or six
months to get back to where you were,
you know, where you were before and
where wherever you were on that
trajectory, too, right? if your levels
were declining wherever that intersects
if it's 5 years later and this is where
you were maybe you're going to be you
know a little bit lower than you were um
you can go you can come off most guys
most guys will um bounce back to some
you know some level of about where they
were before
>> does the TRT dosage has to be adjusted
getting older if I'm now on two clicks
in the morning two clicks in the evening
for the cream is there a chance getting
older that it has to be changed
>> it could be and that can go either way
right that can move either direction,
right? So, um, if your SHBG continues to
go up as you age, and it and it
generally does, right? It's a matter of
does it peak out, but if it's going up,
it's binding up more total testosterone.
You might actually need you might
actually need more.
>> Okay.
>> Um, and then it's a matter of, you know,
how are you reacting to it as as you
age, too? Do you do your symptoms feel
better or worse? In general, you know,
things things can change with people.
Are you are you as fit and active as you
used to be? Um, I really find that
matching testosterone levels to the
level of um, uh, of how well you're
living your life, how optimized you are
just in general. So, you know, for
example, someone who's not and someone
who's not exercising, someone who's
overweight, someone who's, you know, not
doing all these all these other
important lifestyle things, they
probably not going to high handle as as
high a testosterone level as the as the
more fit, active, lean person. Um, but
if you say on top of all those other
things as you age, you're probably fine
to keep you maybe your dose doesn't
change at all. Uh, but the other factor
would definitely be that sex hormone
binding globulin.
>> But in general, I think not not a lot of
big changes. I have a lot of guys that
cruise on the same dose for for many
many years, even as they get older.